<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>alignment on</title><link>/categories/alignment/</link><description>Recent content in alignment on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 21:37:37 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/alignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Language Ex Machina</title><link>/artifacts/language-ex-machina/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 21:37:37 -0800</pubDate><guid>/artifacts/language-ex-machina/</guid><description>Natural Language as Executable Code …then lived upon the stars,
machine-executable,
a brilliant abstraction…
— William Gibson, Fragments of a Hologram Rose
To be analyzed and interpreted, the most recalcitrant material has to be re-presented in a form that can be understood by the machine. Why re-present it at all? Isn’t it sufficient to understand the process of re-presentation?…
— Jane Bennett, Vibrant Matter, p.115-116
The concept of a program existed long before a machine was available to execute it.</description></item><item><title>GPT-3 on Coherent Extrapolated Volition</title><link>/posts/gpt-3-on-coherent-extrapolated-volition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 20:37:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/gpt-3-on-coherent-extrapolated-volition/</guid><description>Coherent Extrapolated Volition is proposal by Eliezer Yudkowsky of an ideal objective function in which an AGI is given the objective of predict(ing) what an idealized version of us would want, “if we knew more, thought faster, were more the people we wished we were, had grown up farther together”. An obvious implementation difficulty is how to encode something so abstract and philosphical in the form of a utility function.</description></item><item><title>HITL thought experiment</title><link>/posts/hitl-thought-experiment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hitl-thought-experiment/</guid><description>HITL = &amp;ldquo;Human in the loop&amp;rdquo;.
This hypertext essay was cowritten with GPT-3 via AI Dungeon in October 2020, before I had API access and before I created the loom. View a map of a subtree of its multiverse here.
Bot credits Coauthor GPT-3 (AI Dungeon) Contribution 9 : 1 Selectivity 1 : 5 This is a thought experiment.</description></item></channel></rss>