<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>prototypes on</title><link>/categories/prototypes/</link><description>Recent content in prototypes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 11:38:32 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/prototypes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Loom: interface to the multiverse</title><link>/posts/loom-interface-to-the-multiverse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 11:38:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/loom-interface-to-the-multiverse/</guid><description>code: github.com/socketteer/loom
paper: Multiversal views on language models
Motivation for the loom Differing from Newton and Schopenhauer &amp;hellip; He believed in an infinite series of times, in a dizzily growing, ever spreading network&amp;hellip; This web of time - the strands of which approach one another, bifurcate, intersect or ignore each other through the centuries - embraces every possibility.
&amp;ndash; The Garden of Forking Paths
I experienced GPT-3 first through AI Dungeon&amp;rsquo;s interface, and like many, I was immediately captivated by the depth, breadth, profundity and - especially given purposeful administration on the part of the user - long-range coherence of the worlds that could be conjured.</description></item><item><title>The Internet, mirrored by GPT-3</title><link>/posts/the-internet-mirrored-by-gpt-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:27:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-internet-mirrored-by-gpt-3/</guid><description>GPT-3 mirrors reality as it has been recorded by humans in text. Unlike a library of text, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t store static records, but rather dynamic virtual realities.
One of the virtual realities folded in GPT-3 is a hallucination of the Internet. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a window into parts of that multiverse that can be represented as Google search results and Wikipedia articles.
Google Given any search query, GPT-3 generates a page of Google search results, complete with urls, preview text, and dates.</description></item></channel></rss>