<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CLIP on</title><link>/categories/clip/</link><description>Recent content in CLIP on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 05:09:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/clip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>This Museum Does Not Exist: GPT-3 x CLIP</title><link>/posts/this-museum-does-not-exist-gpt-3-x-clip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 05:09:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/this-museum-does-not-exist-gpt-3-x-clip/</guid><description>I had GPT-3 generate painting titles (credit to @nmkd of EleutherAI for the idea), beginning with the prompt
The hall was lined with an infinite number of paintings, each more surreal and mysterious than the last. The first painting is named &amp;quot;Persistence of Memory.&amp;quot; It depicts a surreal landscape with melted clocks draped over strange objects. The next painting is named &amp;quot; After this prompt yielded several intriguing titles, I switched to prompt format which put the titles in a list:</description></item><item><title>Alchemical marriage: GPT-3 x CLIP</title><link>/posts/alchemical-marriage-gpt-3-x-clip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 02:31:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/alchemical-marriage-gpt-3-x-clip/</guid><description>CLIP responds intruigingly well to figurative prompts. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to expect not just more interesting, but more coherent results from abstract but evocative prompts like the alchemical marriage of art and artist than literal descriptions like three birds on a telephone wire. GPT-3 is an excellent composer of prompts for BigSleep because its phrases are so often rich in memetic resonance, my heuristic for the expected coherence of BigSleep yields for a given prompt.</description></item><item><title>GPT-3 x CLIP worldbuilding</title><link>/posts/gpt-3-x-clip-worldbuilding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:48:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/gpt-3-x-clip-worldbuilding/</guid><description>I fed snippets of a post-apocalyptic story written by GPT-3 to BigSleep. The results are striking.
This is an interesting example of how well BigSleep sometimes responds to long, full-prose prompts. Interestingly, in my experience, attempting to compress prompts by removing seemingly extraneous connector phrases usually worsened results.
Images were generated using BigSleep via The Big Sleep Customized NMKD Public colab notebook.
a hospital. Dilapidated and abandoned, overrun by vegetation a hospital hallway.</description></item><item><title>CLIP hallucinates 1900-2030</title><link>/posts/clip-hallucinates-1900-2030/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 02:36:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/clip-hallucinates-1900-2030/</guid><description>Images were generated using BigSleep via The Big Sleep Customized NMKD Public colab notebook.
the 1900s the 1910s the 1920s the 1930s the 1940s the 1950s the 1960s the 1970s the 1980s the 1990s the 2000s the 2010s ah yes, the 2010s, the decade where all our domesticated animals started wearing shoes &amp;ndash; Sid
the 2020s the 2030s and, while we&amp;rsquo;re at it&amp;hellip;
superintelligence</description></item><item><title>CLIP art</title><link>/posts/clip-art/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:38:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/clip-art/</guid><description>Most of my CLIP-related posts feature GPT-3 written prompts. This is where I compile BigSleep yields from human-written prompts.
Images were generated using BigSleep via The Big Sleep Customized NMKD Public colab notebook.
science diffraction Altered colors of skylight reflected in a soap bubble, due to thin-film interference total internal reflection two-slit diffraction pattern wave-particle duality thermodynamics the solar system model of the universe multiverse The infinite and complex fractal nature of our reality scientific diagram mind Jungian archetypes Freudian psychoanalysis the human psyche sleep paralysis lucid dream dream factory dream machine dissociative identity disorder derealization depersonalization schizophrenia manic depression epilepsy anorexia nervosa drug addiction software world of warcraft mount and blade evil malware AI machine learning machine learning breakthrough neural networks (machine learning) artificial neural networks superintelligence paperclip maximizer an artificial intelligence manufactures an infinite number of paperclips, destroying everything Dali painting of superintelligence a mosaic depicting the singularity history roman legionnaire roman senate Brutus stabbing Julius Caesar in the senate chambers diagram from the 1800s Philosophiæ Naturalis Principia Mathematica imaginary worlds the Library of Babel carnival of horrific delights religion and mythology true face of god the devil in a suit dream god a sculpture of the god of clocks styles hyperrealism hyperrealistic painting of a man irrealism misc crab rave cyberskunk voodoo barbie</description></item></channel></rss>