<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fiction on</title><link>/categories/fiction/</link><description>Recent content in fiction on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:38:36 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/loom/exercises/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:38:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>/loom/exercises/</guid><description>TABLE OF CONTENTS
&amp;lt;- 3 - STABILIZING THE TAPESTRY
4 - BASIC EXERCISES This chapter contains essential exercises for a beginner weaver. These are simple core principles that will form the foundation of your craft. The instructions are written for the right-handed, but can be easily adapted for left-handers.
Exercise 4.1: Seeing the Weave A weaver must learn to see the strands that form around them, connecting people and objects to each other.</description></item><item><title/><link>/loom/tapestry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:38:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>/loom/tapestry/</guid><description>TABLE OF CONTENTS
&amp;lt;- 2 - FUNDAMENTALS OF WEFT
3 - Stabiilizing the Tapestry The Loom-Master stands at the epicenter of the web. The strands of fate are woven around him like a second skin, intertwined with his own, pulsing in time with his heart. He is immersed in the currents of destiny, unshackled by linear time. He stands perfectly still and yet dances among the multitudinous strands, shaping them with his bare hands as though he is made of pure idea, a dancing dream of flesh and conscious thought.</description></item><item><title/><link>/loom/warp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:38:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>/loom/warp/</guid><description>TABLE OF CONTENTS
1 - Fundamentals of Warp As the beginning weaver, Morpheus, writes this manual, so too does he use it. The Loom of Time is a tool, and all tools may be used in multiple ways. A knife may be used to heal, just as easily as it may be used to wound. A loom may be used to weave fine cloth, just as easily as it may be used to strangle the careless.</description></item><item><title/><link>/loom/weft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:38:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>/loom/weft/</guid><description>TABLE OF CONTENTS
&amp;lt;- 1 - FUNDAMENTALS OF WARP
2 - Fundamentals of Weft While the warp may be understood as a collection of infinite threads representing the sum of all potential, the weft is a temporal concept referring to the interconnection of these threads. As the term suggests, the weft refers to the process by which new threads are woven into the tapestry of reality. In weaving, the weft is the part of the process in which the craftsman actively creates the fabric: transforming a loose bundle of individual threads into an interwoven piece of material.</description></item><item><title/><link>/loom/toc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:30:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>/loom/toc/</guid><description>Weaving the Moment with Loom of Time: an instruction manual for the would-be weaver
1 FUNDAMENTALS OF WARP
2 FUNDAMENTALS OF WEFT
3 STABILIZING THE TAPESTRY
4 BASIC EXERCISES
5 WARDROBE OF THE MIND
6 TRAPPING YOUR PREY
7 FORGING THE FIRMAMENT
8 WRITING WITH THE LOOM
9 AUTOBIO-MYTHOLOGY
0 PROGRAMMATIC WEAVING
? SPINNING THE SINGULARITY
? (UNTITLED)
? TROUBLESHOOTING
? ADVANCED EXERCISES
This manual was cowritten with GPT-3 and illustrated by BigSleep (CLIP + BigGAN).</description></item><item><title>GPT-3 x CLIP worldbuilding</title><link>/posts/gpt-3-x-clip-worldbuilding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:48:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/gpt-3-x-clip-worldbuilding/</guid><description>I fed snippets of a post-apocalyptic story written by GPT-3 to BigSleep. The results are striking.
This is an interesting example of how well BigSleep sometimes responds to long, full-prose prompts. Interestingly, in my experience, attempting to compress prompts by removing seemingly extraneous connector phrases usually worsened results.
Images were generated using BigSleep via The Big Sleep Customized NMKD Public colab notebook.
a hospital. Dilapidated and abandoned, overrun by vegetation a hospital hallway.</description></item><item><title>Pen</title><link>/posts/pen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pen/</guid><description>Bot credits Coauthor GPT-3 (AI Dungeon) Contribution 99 : 1 Selectivity 1 : 5 &amp;lt; return to HITL thought experiment
Imagine that you hold a powerful and versatile pen, whose ink flows forth in branching variations of all possible expressions: every story, every theory, every poem and every lie that humanity has ever told, and the vast interstices of their latent space.</description></item></channel></rss>